Guide to the George Lincoln Burr papers,1861-1942.
Burr, George Lincoln papers, 1886-1942
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George Lincoln Burr papers, 1861-1942.
14-17-22
George Lincoln Burr 1857-1938.
16.8 cubic ft.
Letters, diaries, manuscripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Letters, diary fragments, notes, manuscripts, and other material documenting Burr's boyhood in Newark Valley, New York, and his student days at Cortland Academy, at Cornell University, and at Leipzig University; his travels and activities in Europe collecting rare books and manuscripts for Cornell; his relationship with Andrew Dickson White; his relationships with other American and European scholars and his students; his work for the Venezuela-Guiana Boundary Commission; and his interest in the American Historical Association, the Cornell Alumni Association, the Cornell Christian Association, the Hall of Fame at New York University, the Telluride Association, and in many other social and professional groups.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of medieval history, librarian of the Andrew Dickson White Library at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Letters, diary fragments, notes, manuscripts, and other material documenting Burr's boyhood in Newark Valley, New York, and his student days at Cortland Academy, at Cornell University, and at Leipzig University; his travels and activities in Europe collecting rare books and manuscripts for Cornell; his relationship with Andrew Dickson White; his relationships with other American and European scholars and his students; his work for the Venezuela-Guiana Boundary Commission; and his interest in the American Historical Association, the Cornell Alumni Association, the Cornell Christian Association, the Hall of Fame at New York University, the Telluride Association, and in many other social and professional groups.
Correspondents include Lyman Abbott, Charles Kendall Adams, Roland H. Bainton, Carl Becker, Henry Bourne, James Bryce, John Burroughs, Anna and Henry Comstock, Reverend Robert Collyer, Leonard K. Elmhirst, Livingston Farrand, Max Farrand, Simon Henry Gage, Daniel Coit Gilman, Louis Gottschalk, Evarts B. Greene, Charles Gross, George Willam Harris, Albert Bushnell Hart, Charles Haskins, Ernest Huffcut, Charles Henry Hull, Edward M. Hulme, J. Franklin Jameson (mainly having to do with the AMERICAN HISTORICAL REVIEW), David Starr Jordan (extensive, quite impersonal), Louis C. Karpinski, Horace Kephart, Waldo G. Leland, John Bassett Moore, John R. Mott, David Saville Muzzey, Wallace Notestein, Cuthbert Pound, Herbert Putnam (Library of Congress), Jacob Gould Schurman, George H. Sabine, Goldwin Smith, Preserved Smith, H. Morse Stephens, Dorothy and Willard Straight, Alfred and Ernest Sze, Ida Tarbell, Frederick Jackson Turner, Moses Coit Tyler, Hendrik Willem Van Loon (extensive and intimate), Oswald Garrison Villard, Booker T. Washington, Benjamin Ide Wheeler, Frederick White, Burt G. Wilder, and many others.
Letter, 1903, from Andrew Dickson White about his trip to Elba, with comments about Napoleon I, and fourteen postcards, some annotated, of scenes of Elba.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Burr, George Lincoln,1857-1938.; Abbott, Lyman, 1835-1922.; Bainton, Roland Herbert, 1894-; Becker, Carl Lotus, 1873-1945.; Bourne, H. R. Fox(Henry Richard Fox), 1837-1909.; Bryce, James Bryce, 1838-1922.; Burroughs, John, 1837-1921.; Comstock, Anna Botsford, 1854-1930.; Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1831-1908.; Greene, Evarts Boutell, 1870-1947.; Hart, Albert Bushnell, 1854-1943.; Haskins, Charles Homer, 1870-1937.; Hull, Charles Henry, b. 1864.; Jameson, J. Franklin(John Franklin), 1859-1937.; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931.; Karpinski, Louis Charles, 1878-1956.; Kephart, Horace, 1862-1931.; Moore, John Bassett, 1860-1947.; Mott, John Raliegh, 1865-1955.; Napoleon 1769-1821.; Notestein, Wallace, 1878-1969.; Sabine, George Holland, 1880-1961.; Schurman, Jacob Gould, 1854-1942.; Smith, Goldwin, 1823-1910.; Smith, Preserved, 1880-1941.; Sze, Sao-Ke Alfred, 1877-1958.; Tarbell, Ida M.(Ida Minerva), 1857-1944.; Turner, Frederick Jackson, 1861-1932.; Tyler, Moses Coit, 1835-1900.; Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1882-1944.; Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1872-1949.; White, Fred M.(Fred Merrick), b. 1859.; American Historical Association.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University.Libraries.; Universität Leipzig.
Subjects:
College students.; Rare book libraries.; Rare books.; College teachers.; Historians.; Librarians.
Places:
Guiana--Boundaries.; Newark Valley (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.; Venezuela--Boundaries.; Elba (Italy)--Description and travel--Views.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Additional List of Correspondents
Adams, Charles Francis, 1835-1915
Adler, Cyrus, 1863-1940
Becker, Neal Dow
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
Bryce, James, 1838-1922
Burroughs, John, 1837-1921
Catterall, Ralph Charles Henry, 1866-1914
Cowl, Jane
Curtice, Cooper
Dann, Hollis Ellsworth, 1861-1939
Eggleston, Edward, 1837-1902
Elmhirst, Leonard K.
Gannett, Frank Ernest, 1876-1957
Gladden, Washington, 1836-1918 [directed to Jacob Gould Schurman,*but in Burr Papers]
Jenks, Jeremiah Whipple, 1856-1929
Jernegan, Marcus Wilson, 1872-1949
Jusserand, Jean Adrien Antoine Jules, 1855-1932
Jones, (Rev.) Robert T.
Karpinski, Louis Charles, 1878-1956
Kerr, Abram Tucker, 1873-1938
Kilborne, Fred Lucius, 1857-1936
Kittredge, George Lyman, 1860-1941
Lansing, Robert, 1864-1926
Latourette, Kenneth Scott, 1884-
Lee, Duncan Campbell, 1869-19
Lima, Casimiro Eugenic Amoroso, 1856-1938
Lowell, Abbott Lawrence, 1856-1943
Messenger, Hiram John, 1855-1913
Miller, William Henry, 1848-1922
Mott, John R., 1865-1955
Newman, Jared Treman, 1855-1937
Odell, Benjamin Barker, 1854-1926
Perkins, Dexter, 1889-
Pound, Cuthbert Winfred, 1864-1935
Putnam, Harrington, 1851-1937
Radin, Max, 1880-
Robinson, James Harvey, 1863-1936
Robinson, James Richards, 1885-1953
Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1882-1945
Rose, Stephen Edward
Rothschild, Daniel
Sabine, George Holland, 1880-1961
Schurman, George Wellington, 1877-1931
Silliman, Henry
Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968
Singmaster, Elsie (Mrs. Harold Lewars), 1879-
Speed, Robert Goodloe Harper, 1845-1925
Sutro, Alfred, 1869-1945
Thilly, Frank, 1865-1934
Thompson, James Westfall, 1869-1941
Treman, Robert Henry, 1858-1937
Van Laer, Alexander Theobald, 1857-1920
Washington, Booker Taliaferro, 1859-1915
White, Elwyn Brooks, 1899-
Willcox, Walter Francis, 1861-1964
Williams, Henry Shaler, 1847-1918
Wrench, Jesse Erwin, 1882-1958
*Neither the Burr nor Schurman Papers contain other Gladden letters for this period (Sept. - Oct. 1893, but the Schurman letterbooks contain a copy of one letter from Shcurman to Gladden re preaching at Sage, dated October 26, 1893
Cross references to added entries
Straight, Dorothy Whitney
Capitol fire of 1911 (Albany, New York)
Also,
Cassidy, Owen
Erasmus, Desiderius, 14667-1536
Huffcut, Ernest Wilson, 1860-1907
White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918
Morse Hall (Cornell University)
Russia (travel, 1907)
Travel (Europe)
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Personal Documents and Cornell Material
Series III. Photographs and drawings
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1861-1873 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1874-1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1877-1878 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1879-1881 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
    Including list of medallions, folder 5
  - Correspondence, January-June 8, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, July-August, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, September-December, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, January-July, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, August-December, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, January-April, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, May-September, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, October-December, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, January-February, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, March-May, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Includes 4 letters from Horace Kephart to Burr, from Florence, Italy
  - Correspondence, June-July, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, August-November, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
  - Correspondence, December, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Includes 1 letter from Horace Kephart to Burr, from Florence, Italy. Dated December 16.
  - Correspondence, January, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Includes 1 letter from Horace Kephart to Burr, from Florence, Italy
  - Correspondence, February-July, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence, August-December, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Contains correspondence regarding architectural photos
  - Correspondence, January-July, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence, August, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Contains correspondence regarding the printing of the Reformation catalogue
  - Correspondence, September-December, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, January-June, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 9-12)
  - Correspondence, July-December, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 13-16)
  - Correspondence, January-July, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 17-20)
  - Correspondence, August-December, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
  - Correspondence, January-June, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, July-December, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, January-May, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Correspondence, June-December, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 6-8)
  - Correspondence, January-April, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Correspondence, May-December, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - Correspondence, January-March, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
  - Correspondence, April-May, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Includes correspondence on university photographs
  - Correspondence, June-December, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 16-19)
  - Correspondence, January-May, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 20-22)
  - Correspondence, August-December, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 23-25)
  - Correspondence, January-July, 1895 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, August-December, 1895 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - Correspondence, January-March, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
  - Correspondence, April-May, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
    Includes letters on Venezuela
  - Correspondence, June, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Includes letters on Venezuela and Blue Book
  - Correspondence, July-October, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 12-15)
    Includes letters on Venezuela and Blue Book. Many addressed to Mallet-Prevost
  - Correspondence, November-December, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
  - Correspondence, January-July, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 18-23)
  - Correspondence, August-September, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Includes envelope of photos of Burr's family home
  - Correspondence, October-December, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
  - Correspondence, January-May, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    Includes letters on Venezuela from Mallet-Prevost
  - Correspondence, June-October, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 5-8)
  - Correspondence, November, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Including notes on Saint Lucia, Republican campaign
  - Correspondence, December, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, January, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, February-March, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Related to the building of the new Chapel and Alumni Hall
  - Correspondence, April, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, May, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Including correspondence on Venezuela
  - Correspondence, June-November, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 15-17)
  - Correspondence, December, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Including correspondence on trial of Maria Renata
  - Correspondence, January-October, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 19-21)
  - Correspondence, November-December, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, January, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Includes mention of Professor Tyler's death
  - Correspondence, February-July, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 2-4)
  - Correspondence, August-December, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 5-7)
  - Correspondence, January-February, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 8-10)
  - Correspondence, March-May, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
    Includes two letters from Hendrik Van Loon
  - Correspondence, June-July, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
  - Correspondence, August, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Includes two typescript copies of letters Hendrik Van Loon to E. Bell-Robinson
  - Correspondence, September-December, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 16-19)
  - Correspondence, January-February, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, March-April, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Including a letter and postcards from France, dates March 25.
  - Correspondence, May-October, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 22-24)
  - Correspondence, November-December, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 25-26)
    Including two letters from Win. A. Dunning, one about having Burr fill-in for a lecture in New Orleans and one on Giddings paper
  - Correspondence, January-March, 1904 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, April-September, 1904 (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
  - Correspondence, October-December, 1904 (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
  - Correspondence, January-June, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
  - Correspondence, July-October, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 13-15)
  - Correspondence, November-December, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
  - Correspondence, January-June, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 18-22)
  - Correspondence, July-December, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 23-26)
  - Correspondence, January-March, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 27-28)
  - Correspondence, April 1907 - 1908 (Box 8)
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, March 9, 1908 (Box 8)
    Routine AHA regarding report on annual meetings in Madison
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, May 25, 1908 (Box 8)
    Regarding publication of essays, especially Robertson's
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, April 8, 1908 (Box 8)
    A general letter "To the Members of the Committee on Public; regarding publication of Prize Essays; financing/publishers; great length of essays; wants independent Series
  - Correspondence, 1909 - Oct. 1910 (Box 9)
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, January 8, 1909 (Box 9)
    Regarding Krehbiel's essay; announcement of the series of prize
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, January 18, 1909 (Box 9)
    Details of essay prizes, etc., financial matters; rules
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, January 22, 1909 (Box 9)
    Details on essay correction process
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, January 25, 1909 (Box 9)
    Regarding format of type and page of essays
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, February 17, 1909 (Box 9)
    Sorrow over death of Burr's wife
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, March 5, 1909 (Box 9)
    Regarding Krehbiel's manuscript - editing
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, March 31, 1909 (Box 9)
    Krehbiel's manuscript on way to printer
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, April 5, 1909 (Box 9)
    routine - essays
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, June 27, 1909 (Box 9)
    routine - re proofs (enclosure attached)
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, October 6, 1909 (Box 9)
    Krehbiel's book
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, June 30, 1910 (Box 9)
    Notestein's essay
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, July 10, 1910 (Box 9)
    Notestein's essay (cynical; anti-Semitic)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1910 - 1912 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1913 - Feb. 1915 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1915 - April 1916 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1915 - January 1916 (Box 12)
    Regarding the management of the American Historical Reviews finances. Historian Frederic Bancroft got into an epistolary argument with GLB (treasurer). Burr later referred to this as the "Bancroft Episode."
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, March 5, 1915 (Box 12)
    Looking for new Columbia faculty member
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, May 28, 1915 (Box 12)
    Appointment with Evans
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, January 10, 1916 (Box 12)
    AHA meeting location
  - Correspondence, May 1916 - 1917 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1918 - June 9, 1921 (Box 14)
  - Win. A. Dunning to G.L. Burr, April 14, 1919 (Box 14)
    recommending W.T. Morgan for Eng. History position
  - Correspondence, June 10, 1921 - July 1924 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1924 - May 1927 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, June 1927 - April 1931 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, May 1931 - Aug. 1934 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1934 - Nov. 12, 1938 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, A-K, 1941, 1942 and no date (Box 20)
  - Correspondence L-Z (Box 21)
  - R. Bainton & L.O. Gibbons Research Correspondence re G.L. Burr (Box 22)
- Series II. Personal Documents and Cornell Material
  - Burr Family Material, G.L. Burr Pre-college Days (Box 23)
  - Burr family account book 1848-1856, followed by Burr's class notes and accounts with Cornell library, 1848-1880 (Box 23)
  - Burr's daily diary, partially filled, 1874 (Box 23)
  - Burr's class notebooks, 1873-1875 (Box 23)
  - Burr's notebooks from Homer and Newark, New York (Box 23)
  - Book of handwritten poems, many by Mary Burr, 1828-1829 (Box 23)
  - Hepsy Burr's scrapbook, filled with obituaries and marriages and miscellaneous clippings, 1883-1898 (Box 23)
  - William J. Burr correspondence and writing book, 1835-1902 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Burr family genealogical papers, including sketches, biographies, family records pages from a Bible, and marriage records (Box 23, Folder 2-3)
  - Burr's pre-college notes, clippings, and memorabilia, mainly from Newark, Homer and Cortland, Mid-late 19th century (Box 23, Folder 4-6)
  - Burr's notebooks from lectures at Cornell, 1873-1880 (Box 24)
  - Class of 1881 Treasurer's Book, with notes and correspondence, 1881 (Box 24)
  - Printed lectures and exams (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
  - Printed Cornell material (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Annual Commencement Program 1879, Report of the Librarian, event tickets, Hill Jubilee program, Class Day Exercises 1878, Rules for Students 1878, Resolutions, The Library pamphlet 1883, Exercises for the Class of 1882 and 1879, and other printed pamphlets.
  - Class of 1881 memorabilia, 1881, 1911, 1922, 1929 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Including Burr's oration "Revolt and Revolution"
  - Burr's lecture notes and maps of North America (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Letter book, 1884-1886 (Box 25)
  - Book memoranda (Box 25)
  - Small notebook (Box 25)
  - Book bibliography and memoranda, with small clippings from catalogues, 1885-1888 (Box 25)
  - Diary, 1885 (Box 25)
  - Transcribed copy of Balthasar Hubmaier's "Von Letzern und ihren Verbrennen", October, 1904 (Box 25)
  - Drawing book (Box 25)
  - Burr's description of books (Box 25)
  - Collegien-buch from Leipzig, with diploma folded in the back (Box 25)
  - Note cards of lectures and notes (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
  - Itinerary of Champlain-St. Lawrence excursion, 1883 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Title slips for books used at Basel and in the British Museum, 1890s (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Travel brochures (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Club pamphlet, Cornell invitations, and other Cornell items, 1870-1890 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Photocopies of book memoranda (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Passports from the Department of State, with large watermarks, 1888, 1904, 1912 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Class exams and notes, mainly from Germany, 1880s (Box 25, Folder 9-11)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Notes for Mrs. Hodder's Thesis (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Burr's handwritten copies of "Politics in College" and "The Religious Philosophy of Lucretius" (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Ithaca Congregational Church programs and pamphlets, 1884, 1892, 1894, 1915 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Deposits in the White library, University library, and Christian Association library (incomplete), ca 1880s-1890s (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Burr's application to military training camp, 1915, 1917 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Pedigree form for Burke's Landed Gentry, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Young Men's Youth Association event programs and pamphlets, 1880-1884 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    From New York, Cornell, and Washington DC. Also includes Burr's notes on membership
  - Cornell University Christian Association invitations and pamphlet, 1916 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Includes notes from a lecture Burr gave to C.U.C.A.
  - Note cards on a lecture called "The Living Gospel", possibly given at the Unitarian Church, 1920s (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Notes, pamphlets, reports, and programs from the Unitarian Church (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Includes lecture "Talk on the Devil", "A Historical Development of the Christian Sunday", and "The Living Gospel
  - Reports and copies of correspondence about the Red Cross (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - American Historical Association leaflets and pamphlets, 1884, 1909, 1916, 1932 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Cornell Alumni Trustee nominations and biographies, 1880s-1930s (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Nicola Sacco and Bartolomeo Vanzetti trial leaflets (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Clippings and lecture on the Fred Morelli case, 1921 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    Fred Morelli, class of 1924, took a leave of absence after being attacked by classmates for not wearing his freshman cap. Burr vehemently opposed the use of force and spoke out against the attacks.
  - Biographies and sketches of Cornell faculty and alumni (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Burr's war and Civic Federation lecture notes (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlets, publications and leaflets of events at other universities, 1900s (Box 26, Folder 10, 15)
  - Cornell resolutions, pamphlets, and miscellany, 1880s-1920s (Box 26, Folder 11, 14)
    Includes invitations to events, program for "Alice and Wonderland", exam schedules, course listings, handwritten copy of "All Hal, Cornell!" by E.T. 1903, and petition to not take final exam.
  - War relief materials, 1910-1920 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    Includes war relief brochures, leaflets on Austria aid, documents from the American Relief Administration (including 3 letters from recipients of Christmas food packages), outline for a handbook on relief work for students in Europe, and Cornell Rifle Club announcements
  - Agenda note book, 1896 (Box 26)
  - Ramabai Circle of Cornell University treasurer's book with membership list and pamphlets, 1898-1920 (Box 26)
  - The Imprisonment of Ghent Professors, by Kr. Nyrop, 1917 (Box 26)
  - Telluride Material (Box 27)
  - Notes and clippings on Geology for Warfare of Science (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Notes on education (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Warfare of Science (Box 30)
  - Warfare of Science Notes, Mss., Revisions (Box 31)
  - Venezuelan Boundary Comm. No. 1 (Box 32)
  - Venezuelan Boundary Comm. No. 2 (Box 33)
  - Misc. Reviews, Writings, Bibliographies No. 1 (Box 34)
  - Notes and copies of articles and speeches given by Burr on AD White (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Charles Babcock, Bennett, Irving Church, Collyer, Comstock (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Corson, Crane, Fiske, Hull, Russell, Schurman, Sill, Smith, Tyler, White (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - AD White Obituary by Burr (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Talks by Burr, on White, Cornell, European Archives, and Venezuela (Box 35, Folder 5-6)
  - Loyalty and Liberty, 1919 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    Notes in binder
  - Misc. Reviews, Writings, Bibliographies No. 2 (Box 36)
  - Misc. Scraps, Notes (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous witchcraft notes (Box 38, Folder 1-2)
  - 'New England's place in the History of Witchcraft' by Burr (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - On the Loos MS. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Burr's reviews of witchcraft books (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - "A Witch-Hunt in the Book Shops", by Burr (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - "The Crime of Witchcraft" by Burr, 1923 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - "The Historical Work of Henry C. Lea", by Burr, 1925 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Burr's notes and drafts on introduction to Lea's materials (Box 38, Folder 6-7)
  - "Fragments from the sources- the Witchcraft Persecution" by Burr (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous witchcraft notes (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - "The Historical Work of Henry Charles Lea" by Burr (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Robert Calef materials (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Witchcraft notes and bibliographies (Box 38, Folder 12-17)
  - Materials on Lea and witchcraft (Box 38, Folder 18-19)